CLAUDIO CAMBA

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

claudiocamba.com

github.com/ClaudioCamba

PROFILE

Software Developer with a passion for using code to bring diverse experiences to life. Creative problem solver with over four years experience as a Front End Developer, where I honed my skills in agile development and delivery-focused workflow. In addition to my experience in frontend and backend development my responsibilities included Quality Assurance, A/B testing, Helpdesk support, writing documentation, training and presenting. I seek challenging opportunities in software development to further leverage my technical and analytical skills to produce creative solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer - Northcoders | 11/2023 - Present

- · Developed mobile application using React Native & Supabase for Frontend & Backend
- · Created RESTful API endpoints utilising Node, Express and PostgreSQL
- · Built live full-stack CRUD application, allowing users to create, read, update & delete
- Created reusable components using React, Javascript, SCSS & Bootstrap
- Completed projects Independently and collaboratively (pair programming)
- Conducted code reviews, pull requests to features are quality-assured

Career Break - Travelling Asia & Africa | 04/2023 - 10/2023

• Enhanced my global perspective and adaptability by learning from diverse cultures

Front End Developer - Dentsu Aegis Network | 08/2022 - 03/2023

- Conducted A/B test experiments from feasibility checks, and development through to QA
- Built A/B, MVT and Recommendation (Machine Learning) tests to increase conversion
- Utilised BrowserStack to ensure all tests were quality-assured before going live
- Inspected and provided feedback to peer test builds to guarantee quality consistency
- · Developed reusable and dynamic components utilising front-end technologies

Front End Developer - Cheil Worldwide / Samsung | 01/2019 - 05/2022

- Created A/B tests, personalising consumer experience to improve conversion & revenue
- · Optimised websites based on designs, using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript & Adobe Target
- Performed QA and debug inspections to ensure tracked elements data is correct
- Supported multiple markets by creating in-depth tutorials and code generators
- Responsible for Optimisation implementation during the Samsung Flagship launches
- · Identified brief feasibilities for strategists, to ensure that the project is completed on time
- Managed Jira Service Desk to support markets with queries regarding test builds
- Trained and onboarded Samsung markets on Adobe Target, Confluence and Jira
- Supervised developers to ensure all tests adhered to the company's processes

Junior Front End Developer - Evokeu | 09/2018 - 01/2019

- Transformed designs into functional websites utilising HTML, CSS & jQuery
- Liaised with clients to determine their needs and follow up with regular updates
- · Collaborated with the design team to complete projects within the given timeframe

EDUCATION

The Odin Project - Full Stack Javascript | 2022

• React, NodeJS, Javascript, ES6, Classes, Modules, SCSS & Webpack

Front End Web Development - Treehouse | 2018

- HTML: HTML5, Tables, Forms, Web optimisation & web accessibility
- CSS3: CSS3 Basics, Selectors, Responsive Layout, Flexbox & Bootstrap
- · JavaScript: Ajax Basics, APIs, the DOM, Data Manipulation, Algorithms & jQuery

Bachelor of Arts in Animation - University of Westminster | 2010 - 2013

• Produced films utilising numerous concepts in animation and visual design



CONTACT

London, NW1 07791 778 960 claudiocamba1@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/claudiocamba

SKILLS

Frontend: React, React Native, JavaScript, jQuery, SASS, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Material UI

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL (PSQL), Supabase

Testing | Quality Assurance:Jest.js, Supertest, BrowserStack

Tools | Softwares: Git, Github, Webpack, Vite, Figma, Invision, Netlify, Bitbucket, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Sketch, Atlassian, Confluence, Jira, Monday.com

Concepts | Models: Relational Databases, User Stories, SQL Queries, Pair programming, Object-oriented programming, Functional programming, (MVC) Model View Controller, Version Control, (DOM) Document Object Model, Higher Order Functions, CI/CD, Recursion, Callbacks, Promises, (TDD) Test-Driven Development, (MVP) Minimal Viable Product

A/B Testing Tools: Adobe Target, Dynamic Yield, Visual Website Optimizer (VWO), Optimizely

PROJECTS

dishGo App: React Native and Supabase mobile application to find specific dishes near you.

github.com/ClaudioCamba/dishGo

RESTful API: Fully tested API created with Jest.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL and Express.js.

github.com/ClaudioCamba/be-nc-new